sprend.com 2017-03-04

# Sprend

Summary of what terms and conditions apply when you use our service: 

  * Sprend is a service from Infoflex Transfer AB, a swedish privately held corporation, that enables professional users to send large files.
  * The service may not be used in a way that violates Swedish law.
  * If you choose to register an account you need to share some personal information with us, such as e-mail address and name.
  * The files you send via Sprend are your sole reponsibility and you guarantee that you have the right to use and distribute the files in this way.
  * We do not claim any ownership to any files transfered through our service.
  * When storage time has passed for a file it will be permanently removed from our servers.
  * We respect your privacy and do all that we can to ensure that your files and personal information is safe with us.
  * We use cookies to enable some functionality on the site and we use Google Analytics for anonymous statistics.
  * We never share information about you or your files with any third party unless explicitly required by law.

For more details: 

  * Privacy and integrity
  * Cookies
  * Google Analytics
  * File security

This privacy policy discloses the privacy practices for sprend.com. This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by this web site. It will notify you of the following: 

  * What personally identifiable information is collected from you through the web site, how it is used and with whom it may be shared. 
  * What choices are available to you regarding the use of your data. 
  * The security procedures in place to protect the misuse of your information. 
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information. 

### Information collection, use and sharing

We are the sole owners of the information collected on this site. We only have access to/collect information that you voluntarily give us via email or other direct contact from you. We will not sell or rent this information to anyone. 

We will not share your information with any third party outside of our organization other than required by law. 

We may contact you via email in the future to tell you new features or other changes to our services, or changes to this privacy policy. 

### Information ecurity

We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline. 

Wherever we collect sensitive information (such as credit card data), that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon at the bottom of your web browser, or looking for "https" at the beginning of the address of the web page. 

While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The servers in which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment. 

We use "cookies" on this site. A cookie is a piece of data stored on a site visitor's hard drive to help us improve your access to our site and identify repeat visitors to our site. For instance, when we use a cookie to identify you, you would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information on our site. 

We use a tool called “Google Analytics” to collect information about use of this site. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit this site, what pages they visit when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to this site. We use the information we get from Google Analytics only to improve this site. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this site, rather than your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics with personally identifiable information. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit this site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy. You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to this site by disabling cookies on your browser. 

  1. All files are stored on our equipment / servers in Sweden. 
  2. Database (user and file data) and files are stored on different servers. 
  3. Files are normally stored exactly as they are uploaded. This means that in order to have highest end-to-end security you need to encrypt files before you upload them and share encryption key with the recipient through other means.   
The easiest way to encrypt files is usually to create a password-protected zip archive. 
  4. With Sprend Pro you can choose to password protect a file on upload. This means that the file will be encrypted before stored on disk and the recipient needs to provide the right password (encryption key) before being able to download the file.   
In this case you would have to trust us that we indeed encrypt the uploaded file. So, this would be a bit weaker than "2.".   
By default we will never see the encryption keys but you can choose to store the encryption key in the database for convenience (and at the price of lower security). 
  5. Anyone that gets hold of the download link can download the file (even though it may be encrypted and in that case, hopefully, useless). 
  6. User passwords are stored as salted SHA1 hashes in the database.
